<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rdcomclient on notpeerreviewed</title>
    <link>/categories/rdcomclient/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rdcomclient on notpeerreviewed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/rdcomclient/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RDCOMClient Part 7 - [[&#34;Value&#34;]] vs [[&#34;Text&#34;]]</title>
      <link>/2018/11/rdcomclient-part-7-gotchas-value-vs-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/rdcomclient-part-7-gotchas-value-vs-text/</guid>
      <description>This post will be a bit shorter than usual, but I thought it could be useful to highlight a potential ‘gotcha’ that could cause problems for newcomers to RDCOMClient.
A Range object includes several properties, including Value and Text. What’s the difference between between Value and Text? The help page explains things quite well.
Basically there’s two differences. Firstly, if your specified Range object covers multiple cells, the Text property will only return the value in the first cell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDCOMClient Part 6 - Writing arrays to Excel</title>
      <link>/2018/11/rdcomclient-part-6-writing-arrays-to-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/rdcomclient-part-6-writing-arrays-to-excel/</guid>
      <description>My last post covered a bit more detail on how to specify colours to be passed to Excel for formatting your data. This post I’ll get back to using RDCOMClient to write data into your Excel documents.
Specifically I want to cover the following:
writing arrays to a specified rangetype specificationwriting dates to ExcelWe already know how to open an existing Excel workbook, or create one from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDCOMClient Part 5 - Extending colour formatting</title>
      <link>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-5-extending-colour-formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-5-extending-colour-formatting/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I introduced creating a new Excel workbook, writing data into that workbook, and applying some formatting to that data. In this post I’ll cover the following:
Simplifying the colour specificationSaving your workbookSimplifying colour specificationAs we saw in the previous post, it is a bit difficult telling Excel what colour to use for something. You need to know the exact numeric reference for a colour and unless you have identified the colour through trial and error previously, it’s just not something you want to be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDCOMClient Part 4 - Writing data to Excel</title>
      <link>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-4-writing-data-to-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-4-writing-data-to-excel/</guid>
      <description>In the last few posts we’ve covered how to read data from Excel into R. In this post we’ll start looking at how to write data into Excel using RDCOMClient. Generally speaking, it is quite easy to write from R to Excel using this package, but there are a few key things to remember.
In this post I’ll cover the following:
creating a new Excel document from Rwriting data to a specified rangebasic formatting of your dataCreating a new Excel documentThis is no different to what we’ve done in the past few posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDCOMClient Part 3 - Find()</title>
      <link>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-3-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-3-find/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I looked at how to use the UsedRange() method to create a range from which we could read the Values. In this post we’ll look at how we can reduce the size of the range by choosing only the parts of range we know we need.
If you know that there is a cell within your data that always carries the same value, you can use that as a key reference when building a range object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDCOMClient Part 2 - UsedRange()</title>
      <link>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/rdcomclient-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I covered how to open Excel and read some basic data. In this post I’m going to look at the UsedRange method.
Firstly, I want to go through how to find these methods. The RDCOMClient package makes mention of the package SWinTypeLibs. This package is supposed to allow access to the list of all available methods and properties from a particular object. I have yet to be able to get this package to work on my machine so I have resorted to using the Object browser from the Excel VBA interface to identify methods and properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to RDCOMClient</title>
      <link>/2018/10/introduction-to-rdcomclient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/introduction-to-rdcomclient/</guid>
      <description>For years I have been saying to myself - “I really should start a blog”. Recently I stumbled across the blogdown package and finally decided I had a simple enough tool to help me get started.
One Saturday night later and I am up and running with a functional blog. Fast forward a few months and here we are. I’ve decided that the best topic for me to write about first is the RDCOMClient package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>